Listen up, Akemitsu.
听好了 明光
No one can live just by themselves.
人是无法独自生存于这个世上的
Dad, what are you talking about?
爸爸 你怎么突然说这个呀
Akemitsu, you're part of the Akagami family, so you should understand.
明光 你也是赤神家的人 应该能明白我说的话
Two is better than one, and more is better than just two.
一个人不如两个人 两个人不如更多人
You would also like more friends, right?
你应该也觉得朋友越多越好对吧
So I'm thinking
所以我就想啊
it's better to have more lovers.
恋人肯定也是越多才越好
Dad, you're so cool!
爸爸 你好帅
Someone's here to pick me up.
好像有人来接我了
Dad, are you going somewhere?
爸爸 你要出去吗
Yes.
没错
I've decided to live my own life!
爸爸我呀 决定去过自己的人生了
I'm going to fall in love with girls I've never seen before in the world.
我要去和世界上未曾谋面的 女孩子们相亲相爱了
Dad, you're so cool!
爸爸 你好帅 真的超帅的
Wow, Dad!
哇哦 爸爸
WORLDLY DESIRES
(世俗杂念)
(TenPuru -No one can live on loneliness-)
《妙庙美少女》
(Episode 1: Pay with Body)
(第一话 决定用身体来偿还了)
So funny.
好好笑
I have to go to university now!
我得去大学上课了
ZEN WEEKLY
(禅秀周刊)
My father said,
我父亲曾说过
no one can live just by themselves.
人是无法独自生存于这个世上的
Two more laps!
还有两圈
-Oh my. -Oh man.
-真不错呀 -就是说啊
-What a nice butt. -Yeah.
-真是美好的屁股呀
Oh, Akagami.
喂 赤神
Come take a look.
你也过来看看嘛
Sorry, I need to work.
抱歉 我要打工
Still the same old Akagami.
赤神这家伙 还真是一点也没变
Hey, do you want to go to a mixer?
喂 你要去联谊吗
No.
我不去
CIVIL SERVICE EXAM MATERIALS No need! No need! No need!
(公务员考试资料) 不需要 不需要 不需要
I, Akagami Akemitsu, don't need women in my life.
我赤神明光的人生中不需要女人
LONELY MART Thank you.
多谢惠顾
Sorry for asking you to make the shift, Akagami.
赤神 临时让你换班 真是不好意思
It's okay, boss..
没关系的 店长
But is it really okay to keep you so late?
不过你打工到这么晚 这样真的好吗
Don't you have a date with your girlfriend or something?
大学生一般不是都会 去和女朋友约会什么的…
I'm single!
我崇尚单身主义
Really?
真的还假的
When your dad was your age…
你爸像你这么大的时候啊…
I'm not like my dad.
我爸是我爸 我是我
LONELY MART So-sorry.
(单身超商) 抱…抱歉
Welcome!
欢迎光临
Dad, you're so cool!
爸爸 你好帅
That scumbag old man.
那个变态人渣老爹
What's cool about him? I was so naive at five!
根本就不帅嘛 我五岁的时候还真是幼稚
It's all because of that old man.
因为那个人渣老爹
He made me feel shameful wherever I go.
害我不知道背上了多少耻辱
Akagami Akemitsu is…
赤神明光是…
Ah, he's from that family!
哎呀 是那一家
No! He's gonna violate me!
不要啊 我要被赤神侵犯
I'll clear this stain myself.
这个污名就由我来洗刷
MIXER GIRLFRIEND Mixer? Girlfriend?
联谊 女朋友
Those are just burdens!
那些都不过是累赘而已
I'll live a magnificent life alone!
我要独自一个人华丽地活下去
I'll pass the national civil service exam,
我要通过国家公务员考试
CIVIL SERVICE EXAM MATERIALS obtain a stable income
(公务员考试资料) 从而得到稳定的收入
And after that…
然后 在那之后
CIVIL SERVICE EXAM MATERIALS After that…
在那之后…
Hey!
等一下
Where did this bag of rice come from?
这是哪来的米袋
I'm sorry.
对不起
Are you okay? Are you injured?
没事吧 你有没有受伤
I'm really sorry! The cart flipped.
我不小心把手推车弄倒了 真的很抱歉
Um…
那个…
Can you stand up?
你站得起来吗
Is there any pain?
有没有哪里痛
What should I do?
怎么办呢
Anyway, I'll call an ambulance first…
总之我先叫救护车来…
I'm fine.
我没什么事
It's okay, it's okay.
我没事 我没事
Wait a minute!
等一下
Not good, not good, not good.
不妙不妙不妙不妙
I can't believe I faltered so easily.
没想到我定力居然这么差
This is not good.
这下不妙了
Oh heck!
老子我啊啊啊
So cute.
好可爱
The last lap!
还剩一圈
Let's go watch the girls today.
我们今天也去养养眼吧
Sounds good.
好啊
Akagami?
赤神
So sexy.
真性感啊
We're going to the mixer.
我们要去联谊
You're not going, right?
我记得赤神你说你不会去嘛…
I'm going.
我要去
-Really? What about class? -Not attending.
-真的吗 那课呢 -不上了
-What about your work? -Not going.
-打工呢 -不去了
Cheers!
干杯
WANT TO DO THIS AND THAT ENTWINED IN DESIRE
(这个也想做那个也想做) (欲望缠身)
What am I doing?
我在干什么啊
I fell in love at first sight with that girl!
我竟然会对那个女生一见钟情
Now all I think about every day is her.
现在我每天脑子里想的全是她
I was hit by a wave of worldly desires!
世俗的杂念如波涛般向我袭来
I got fired from my part-time job before I realized it!
等我回过神来 我的打工不但被开除了
FOR SKIPPING WORK
(因为翘班) 就连大学的学分也落下了好多
FOR SKIPPING CLASSES
(因为逃学)
Is this the curse of the Akagami family?
这就是赤神家的诅咒吗
NOT REALLY
(并不是)
INCOMING CALL
(来电中)
Hello?
喂喂
Mixer? I'll be there in a minute.
联谊吗 我马上到
Damn it!
可恶啊
Looks like there's only one way!
看来 只有那一个方法了
DEAN'S OFFICE
(教务处)
LEAVE OF ABSENCE REQUEST
(休学申请书)
Are you serious?
你是认真的吗
Yes.
是的
ZEN WEEKLY Becoming a monk…
(禅秀周刊) 出家去修行…
Have you found a temple already?
你已经找好寺庙了吗
My uncle used to be an abbot.
我找我之前当过住持的叔叔商量后
He even prepared my monk's robe after I told him!
他连袈裟都借给我了
There must be some other way
消除世俗杂念的方法
to eliminate worldly desires.
应该不只有这一种吧
If you want to start from scratch,
要想从头锻炼自己
Is this the place?
就是这里吗
I'll practice Buddhism at the temple my uncle introduced
我要在叔叔介绍给我的寺庙
and avoid all contact with women.
进行女宾止步的佛教修行
That way, I won't be obsessed with her again.
这样一来 我就不会再鬼迷心窍了
Please!
拜托了
Yes?
来了
May I help you?
请问你有什么事吗
Um, wait…
那个 等一下
Geez! Is this a prank or something?
真是的 你是来恶作剧的吗
Monk's robe? Um, no way.
袈裟…呃 不会吧
Please wait for a moment!
请你稍微等我一下
Why is she here?
为什么她会出现在这
There shouldn't be any women here, right?
这里不是女宾止步的吗
Is it a hallucination caused by my desires?
这是杂念让我产生的幻觉吗
I'm sorry to keep you waiting.
让您久等了
Please excuse my rudeness.
刚刚我有些慌乱 真是失礼了
Thank you for coming all this way.
感谢您不远万里来到这里
My name is Aoba Yuzuki.
我的名字是苍叶结月
Eh, where are you going?
请问 您要去哪里
Are you okay?
您没事吧
No, this won't do!
不行不行 这样可不行
I can still hold back only because I'm trying to!
现在还能忍住不那个 都是因为我在那个啊
-I'm sorry, my kimono is a bit… -Don't look!
-抱歉 我的和服有些… -我不能看
I have to get out of here quickly! I need to…
我要赶紧离开这里 要赶紧…
Hurry… up…
赶紧…紧…紧…
I love you! Please marry me!
我喜欢妳 请妳和我结婚
What?
啥
(TenPuru -No one can live on loneliness-) LIFE HAS UPS AND DOWNS
《妙庙美少女》 (人生既有高潮又有低谷)
Please.
请用
Thank you.
多谢
What's going on?
这是什么情况
Why is she serving me tea?
为什么她给我敬上茶了
I did imagine how it would be to become a disciple.
我还以为皈依佛门会是这样的情节…
-Please take me as your disciple! -Get out!
-请收我为弟子 -给我滚出去
I'm sorry. The abbot is not here today.
不好意思 住持现在刚好不在
I heard you were coming tomorrow.
我听说您是明天才要过来
I see.
原来如此
UNCLE Did uncle tell them the wrong time?
(叔叔) 是叔叔通知时出了什么差错吗
So… um…
那么…呃…
Still, I wonder who this person is.
话说回来 这个人到底是谁
What are your hobbies?
请问您有什么兴趣吗
A question?
她怎么会问我问题
Is she the examiner for the entrance exam?
难道她是入门考试的考官吗
PASS OR FAIL They brought a woman to the temple
(是否合格) 在女宾止步的场合故意找来女性
just to test my reaction.
为的就是要测试我的反应
Oh no, this is bad.
糟了 这下糟了
I proposed after just arriving.
我刚来寺庙时 才过几秒钟就向她求婚了
I'll definitely fail this time.
这下绝对不合格了
Is… Is anything wrong?
请…请问您怎么了吗
She's so cute.
她真的超可爱
What… what's wrong?
这…您怎么了
I just had a bit of worldly desires.
我只是产生了一点世俗的杂念
Where is the restroom?
请问洗手间在哪里呢
The restroom? Outside, to the left.
洗手间的话 出去后左转就到了
Oh no, what should I do?
糟了糟了 怎么办
The courtyard is so beautiful.
好漂亮的庭院
Is it here?
这里吗
You can't come up?
你上不来了吗
It is a bit hard to reach you.
确实是有点难碰到…
Hello, Kiki?
喂 嬉嬉姐吗
What's wrong? Listen to me.
妳还问我怎么了 我说啊
My blind date came a day early for some reason.
我相亲的对象 不知为什么今天就过来了
This is my first blind date.
这可是我第一次相亲耶
He started by saying he wants to marry and all.
他一上来就说要结婚什么的
Kiki, you're the matchmaker.
嬉嬉姐 妳是媒人吧
Then hurry back and help me.
那妳就赶快回来帮帮我嘛
Wait, what are you talking about?
等等等等 妳在说什么呢
Your blind date partner is right next to me now.
妳的相亲对象 现在就在我旁边哦
Then who is that person…
那么 那个人到底是…
Yuzuki? Hello? Yuzuki?
结月 喂 结月
I'm back.
我回来了
Tsukuyo!
月夜
Yuzuki, your blind date is today?
结月姐 妳相亲是在今天吗
I wanted to get a sneak peek at him.
我原本还想说要在旁边偷看呢
An evil spirit has appeared!
庙里出现恶灵了
Ah?
啥
Or it could be some vengeful spirit.
或者是怨灵作祟之类的…
What are you talking about?
妳在说什么呢
How could there be…
怎么可能会有…
Help… me…
救…命…
Tsukuyo, run!
月夜 快跑
Evil spirit, begone!
恶灵退散
This way!
这边
Wh-wh-what is that?
那那那那那是什么啊
I told you there's an evil spirit!
我就跟妳说恶灵出现了嘛
It's a misunderstanding!
误会 这全都是误会
Where did you go?
你跑去哪里了呢
Sis?
姐姐
-Kurage! -Run!
-海月 -快跑
Kagura, bring me the ink brush.
神乐 拿笔给我
Yes, here.
好的 给您
Miss Mia, what is this?
米亚小姐 这是
NOZAWA MASAKO
(野泽雅子) 这个读作大和抚子哦
Only a true lady who survives
这是在竞争激烈的 配音业界生存下来的
in the fiercely competitive voice acting industry can get this title.
真正的淑女 才能获得的称号
This is what we should strive for.
这也是我们要争取的呢
What's going on? So noisy!
你们在做什么 真的很吵耶
Wha-what happened?
发…发生了什么
-What's with this guy? -Oh my.
-这…这家伙是怎么回事 -哎呀哎呀
-Get off of me already! -I must…
-快起来 我叫你起来啊 -必须要…
-Kagura, don't just watch, help me! -… clear up the misunderstanding.
-神乐 妳别光看着啊 来帮帮我 -解开误会
So funny.
好好笑
Is this the right time to laugh?
现在是该笑的时候吗
That was Mia?
刚才的声音 是米亚吗
What do we do? Another victim of the evil spirit.
怎么办啊 恶灵的牺牲品又多了一个
And we left Kurage behind.
我们还把海月丢下不管
I think he ran straight past Kurage.
他好像直接从海月身边跑过去了
Why is he targeting us?
那他为什么会盯上我们了啊
What's different between Kurage and us?
海月和我们有什么不一样吗
If there's any difference…
要说不一样…
It's a perverted evil spirit!
这是哪来的好色恶灵啊
But if he really is an evil spirit,
但如果他真的是恶灵
my kick should have gone right through him.
刚刚我的飞踢 应该会直接穿透他才对
If I explain it properly,
好好解释一下的话
they will surely understand.
她们肯定能理解的
It's not like that, I…
不是这样的 我…
She's still so cute.
她果然还是好可爱啊
Damn it.
可恶
You were mistaken for a pervert, that's so funny!
你居然被当成变态了 这也太好笑了吧
He came here to practice
他是透过叔叔的介绍
because of his uncle's recommendation.
才把这里当成修行的场所前来的
Yuzuki saw his robe
而结月看到他的袈裟
and mistook him for the blind date partner who should come tomorrow.
就误以为他是 提前一天过来的相亲对象
That's right.
是的
So whose fault is it?
那么 这到底是谁的责任呢
Of course it's your fault, you forgot to introduce us.
那肯定是忘了介绍的 嬉嬉姐妳的责任啊
I can't believe you could get your blind date wrong.
连相亲对象都能搞错 妳也真是够胡涂的
You said it wasn't necessary to see the blind date's picture!
谁叫妳之前跟我说 相亲对象的照片就算不看也没关系啊
His uncle is really unreliable.
他叔叔也真是的
MEN FORBIDDEN How could he not know this is a nunnery
(男宾止步) 连这里是个尼姑庵都不知道
and recommend his nephew to come.
就推荐他侄子过来了
Nun-nery…
尼…姑…庵
So…
那…那个…
Although it was a misunderstanding,
虽说是搞错了
I did hit you with a flying kick and a palm strike.
但我毕竟还是飞踢了你 而且还赏了你一巴掌
-I'm really sorry… -It's fine.
-实在是非常… -这倒是没关系
But what's wrong with you two?
不过这二位是怎么了
Well, there are some things
那个 对少女来说
that are intolerable for young girls.
有些事就算是意外 也是无法容忍的
Alright, how about this?
好了 那就这样吧
Since both of you are at fault,
既然你们双方都有错
why don't we let him practice here for a while?
那就让他在这里 暂时修行一段时间怎么样
What?
什么
Are you serious, Kiki?
妳说这话是认真的吗 嬉嬉姐
This is a nunnery!
这里可是尼姑庵耶
We can just take down the sign that says 'Men Forbidden'.
拿掉那块写着男宾止步的牌子 不就好了吗
Just like that?
就这么简单吗
You must want it too, right?
妳们难道不想要吗
Free male labor?
免费的男性劳动力
But… but…
但…但是…
I would like some helping hands.
我倒是想轻松一点
But it's not okay to have him here.
就算嬉嬉姐妳这么想也不行啊
Be honest, you two.
你们两个都坦诚一点吧
It seems to be going well.
奇怪 这件事好像还挺顺利的
Living with this man…
和这个男人同居…
Alright, alright, put it away.
好了好了 收起来收起来
Kiki, you'll be in danger too.
嬉嬉姐妳也会有危险的
This guy only has breasts in his eyes!
这人的眼里就只有胸部耶
Really? Let me try.
是吗 我试试
Stop it!
妳不要试啊
This guy just told me
这个人刚才对我说
that he…
说他…
lo-lo-lofe…
喜…喜…喜…喜饭…
Lofe?
什么稀饭
Um, thank you very much.
那个 非常感谢你们
Is it really okay?
这样真的好吗
Yeah, I can't keep causing trouble for you.
嗯 我不能再继续给你们添麻烦了
And…
而且…
She probably doesn't remember
她也不可能记得
our first meeting.
我们第一次见面的事情吧
Goodbye.
再见啦
Sis Yuzuki.
结月姐
Nyagosuke said it's a pity.
喵之助说牠很遗憾呢
I don't think he's a bad person either.
我也觉得那个人不是什么坏人
Maybe.
也许是吧
The last bus is gone.
公交车的班次果然早就没了
What have I done?
我都干了些什么啊
What should I do after this?
我之后该怎么办呢
Yeah, what should you do?
对呀 你要怎么办呀
Ah, like I thought.
啊 果然
This place is in the suburbs.
因为这里非常乡下
The buses are gone very early.
所以公交车的班次很早就没有了呢
W-What is it?
妳…妳还有什么事吗
Do you want to stay over for one night?
你要不要来我们这借住一晚呢
Ah, no.
你看嘛
We are both at fault for what happened.
这次是因为我们双方的疏失 所以才会发生这种事
And our temple is quite spacious.
而且我们的寺庙也还挺宽敞的
You can't stay long though.
虽然没办法让你长居就是了
I'll persuade the others, okay?
就由我来说服大家吧 如何
Seems like she's a really nice person.
我看人的眼光好像还是不错的
Thank you very much.
非常感谢妳
But I want to try my best on my own first.
但是 我想试着先自己努力看看
I see.
这样啊
I don't want to use her as an excuse to avoid the problem.
我不想把她当成逃避的理由
By the way, I was really surprised.
话说回来 我还真是吓了一大跳呢
So much happened just after we met.
没想到一见面就发生了这么多事
I'm sorry, please forget everything!
对不起 请妳都忘掉吧
How can you ask me to forget?
叫我忘掉 那你还真是有点绝情呢
I'm sorry.
对不起
You see, we've only met twice, and you're talking about marriage.
我们明明才见过两次面而已 你就说要跟我结婚
She still remembers.
她竟然还记得…
What kind of joke is that?
真是的 这是哪门子的玩笑嘛
MIKAZUKI TEMPLE STATION Huh?
咦
Uh, it was a joke, right?
呃 你是开玩笑的吧
-Um… -Yeah!
-那个… -什么事
My name…
名字…
Your name?
什么名字
My name is Akagami Akemitsu.
我的名字是赤神明光
Right, I don't know your name yet.
对喔 我还不知道你的名字呢
We were really in a panic.
我们真的是太慌乱了呢
Let me introduce myself again. My name is Aoba Yuzuki.
我再重新自我介绍一下 我叫苍叶结月
Nice to meet you.
请妳多多关照
Akagami?
赤神…
Akagami… Is it…
赤神 你该不会…
I'll try with all my life to pay back
我父亲留下的两千万欠款
the 20 million yen debt my father left!
我会赌上性命全部偿还的
I'm really sorry!
实在是非常抱歉
Alright, calm down.
好了好了 冷静冷静
Who would have thought
没想到这家伙
this guy is the son of the man
竟然是那个借了寺庙的钱后
who borrowed money from the temple and ran away?
就跑了的男人的儿子
Listen to me, everyone.
大家听我说
SLAVE He couldn't possibly
(人口) 他不可能马上
pay back so much money right away.
就还清这么多钱
But we can't just let him off the hook, right?
但是 我们也不能 就这样放过他 对吧
SELL AS A SLAVE, SELL HIS ORGANS So now there are two more humane ways
(人口贩卖 器官买卖) 所以现在有这两种
for him to repay the debts.
更人道的还款方式
SELL AS A SLAVE, SELL HIS ORGANS Let's take a vote.
(人口贩卖 器官买卖) 请大家举手表决
Sell as a slave!
人口贩卖
Sell his organs!
器官买卖
If we're going to sell,
既然要卖的话
it's better to preserve his dignity.
还是保留人的尊严会更好吧
He looks like he can make money for many years.
毕竟他看起来还能赚很多年的钱
Kurage! What are you saying?
海月 妳在说什么呢
Anyway, after thorough consideration,
总之 我想来想去
we decided to let Akagami pay with his body.
最后还是决定让赤神用身体来偿还
Huh?
咦
NEXT EPISODE (Being Lewd Is Not A Bad Thing)
(下集 色色不是什么坏事哦)
First, take off your clothes.
首先把衣服脱掉
Why?
为什么
Akagami, please take yours off too.
赤神也要脱掉衣服
It's easier to enter when it's wet.
这样变湿以后就方便进入了
Why?
为什么啊啊啊
Being lewd is not a bad thing.
色色不是什么坏事哦